<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Travel - Tag - Guy Evans</title><link>https://guy-evans.com/tags/travel/</link><description>Travel - Tag - Guy Evans</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 14:24:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://guy-evans.com/tags/travel/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Onebag for Travel - Whats in my 2023/2024 travel bag</title><link>https://guy-evans.com/posts/2023-12-10_onebag-for-travel-whats-in-my-2023-travel-bag/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 14:24:11 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Guy Evans</name><uri>https://guy-evans.com</uri><email>web@evans.fr</email></author><guid>https://guy-evans.com/posts/2023-12-10_onebag-for-travel-whats-in-my-2023-travel-bag/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/2023-12-10_onebag-for-travel-whats-in-my-2023-travel-bag/feature.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><h2 id="too-many-bags" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#too-many-bags" class="header-mark"></a>Too many bags</h2><p>I am a fan of travelling, although I haven&rsquo;t been able to travel much since the birth of the little one but I digress.</p>
<p>Back to Onebag travel: Many of us have dealt with the hassle of managing multiple, often large bags while travelling. How often have you arrived at a destination before being able to check in to your accommodation? In such cases, I usually start exploring the destination, but the challenge is dealing with large bags. Ideally, you can either A) leave your bags at your accommodation, B) find a bag storage location, or C) wait until you can check in.</p>
<h2 id="onebag-travel" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#onebag-travel" class="header-mark"></a>Onebag Travel?</h2><p>But what if I told you there is another way? Well there is &hellip; get rid of all but one bag.</p>
<p>Onebag travel, also known as one-bagging, is a minimalist approach to travel that involves packing and travelling with only a single piece of luggage, typically a carry-on-sized backpack or suitcase. The goal is to simplify the travel experience by minimizing the amount of belongings one carries, focusing on essential items, and avoiding the need for multiple bags or checked luggage.</p>
<h3 id="why-onebag-travel" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#why-onebag-travel" class="header-mark"></a>Why Onebag Travel?</h3><p>Now we know what Onebag travel is, here a just a few upsides:</p>
<p>Cost Savings: Many airlines charge fees for checked baggage. By adhering to carry-on limits, onebag travelers can avoid these fees, contributing to cost savings.</p>
<p>Time Savings: Without the need to check or retrieve multiple bags, onebag travelers can move through airports more quickly, potentially reducing travel time.</p>
<p>Flexibility: Onebag travel encourages a mindset of simplicity. Travelers learn to prioritize essentials, making it easier to adapt to different situations and environments.</p>
<h2 id="the-bag" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#the-bag" class="header-mark"></a>The Bag</h2><p>Okay so now we know about onebag travel and some of its advantages, we need to choose a bag. I&rsquo;ll spare you most of my research as everyone has different criteria. Here are mine:</p>
<p>The bag:</p>
<ul>
<li>be cheap - no more than 100 Euros</li>
<li><strong>MUST</strong> fit in most airline carry-on requirements</li>
<li>fit a 4 days worth of clothes minimum</li>
<li>carry a laptop if needed</li>
<li>be comfy</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="so-research-time-i-guess" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#so-research-time-i-guess" class="header-mark"></a>So research time I guess?</h3><figure><img src="/img/going-to-need-more-coffee-bbt.gif">
</figure>

<p>I started my research on reddit (as I usually do) and quickly stumbled on a goldmine; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/onebag/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">r/onebag</a>, a reddit community dedicated to onebagging.</p>
<p>After hours of browsing a bag caught my eye - The Decathlon NH500 Escape 23L Rolltop which checked most of my requirements:</p>
<ul>
<li>Cheap - 49 Euros in Store</li>
<li>Fits plenty</li>
<li>Can carry a laptop and tablet</li>
<li>Roll-top - Can be expanded from 23L to something like 30L</li>
<li><em>Bonus</em>: designed by Decathlon, a french company &#x1f1eb;&#x1f1f7; and available in their stores</li>
</ul>
<p>After some browsing I actually bought mine on Vinted for 35 Euros so a win win I guess.
<figure><img src="/posts/2023-12-10_onebag-for-travel-whats-in-my-2023-travel-bag/sac-a-dos-de-randonnee-23l-nh-escape-500-rolltop.jpg">
</figure>
</p>
<h2 id="the-contents" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#the-contents" class="header-mark"></a>The Contents</h2><figure><img src="/posts/2023-12-10_onebag-for-travel-whats-in-my-2023-travel-bag/IMG_4754.jpeg">
</figure>

<p>Now the fun part what do we put in the bag? Here is my base list. I won&rsquo;t go into detail for each item but I will include some thoughts for some items.</p>
<h3 id="packing-cubes" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#packing-cubes" class="header-mark"></a>Packing cubes</h3><p><figure><img src="/posts/2023-12-10_onebag-for-travel-whats-in-my-2023-travel-bag/IMG_4756.jpeg">
</figure>

I usually use 2 packing cubes:</p>
<ul>
<li>1 <a href="https://amzn.to/48k3dRM" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Peak Design Medium</a> for clothes</li>
<li>1 Small cheap Ono cube for underwear and socks.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="clothes" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#clothes" class="header-mark"></a>Clothes:</h3><p>Here is my clothes list, usually good for 4 days and autumn temperatures. Could also work for colder temps.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>2 Polo shirts, 1 blue and 1 white</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>2 Normal Cotton t-shirts (1 worn for travel)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>2 Uniqlo Airisism Cotton t-shirts - these are great for travel as they fold up small</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>1 Uniqlo Beige Jeans - these easily can pass as chinos in a pinch</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>1 Uniqlo Ultra Stretch Jeans (Worn) - these are some of the comfiest jeans for travel.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Plenty of underwear - I had two extra</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Socks:</p>
<ul>
<li>1 pair Darn Tough Socks (Merino)</li>
<li>1 pair Smartwool (Merino)</li>
<li>2 pairs of cheap socks for backup</li>
</ul>
<p>The key here as I&rsquo;ve learnt recently is merino wool. Merino wool is lightweight, durable, odor resistant and antimicrobial and breathable.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Smart looking Primark Jumper</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Zip-Up Hoody (Worn)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Running shorts that double as swim shorts (not shown)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://amzn.to/49SGz3u" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Patagonia Nano-Puff Jacket</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Arc’teryx baseball cap - great for rain and sunny weather</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Adidas Advantage shoes - once broken in they are so comfy</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="electronics" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#electronics" class="header-mark"></a>Electronics:</h3><ul>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/3TkAAiZ" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Anker PowerCore 20 000 mAh battery</a> - way too big but a nice to have</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/4ansg7Y" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Anker 40W USB C Charger</a></li>
<li>Lightning to USB C</li>
<li>Apple Watch Cable</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/4alrgBh" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">USB C cable</a></li>
<li>Apple Airpods pros</li>
<li>Spare wired headphones + lightning to headphone jack</li>
<li>4G wifi router - bought for friends as I get a lot of data in the EU</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/48i9yyi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon Kindle Paperwhite</a></li>
<li>Flashlight: D4v2 - always have a decent flash light … don’t ask 😉</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="hygiene" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#hygiene" class="header-mark"></a>Hygiene:</h3><ul>
<li>Toothbrush + bought toothpaste on arrival</li>
<li>Shower-gel</li>
<li>Deodorant</li>
<li>Contact lens solution and case</li>
<li>Disposable razor</li>
<li>Paracetamol</li>
<li>Ear-plugs</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="misc" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#misc" class="header-mark"></a>Misc:</h3><ul>
<li>Sunglasses</li>
<li>Glasses - for when I don’t wear contact lenses.</li>
</ul>
<p>Do you travel with one or more bags? What&rsquo;s in your travel bag(s)?</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Note: some links may be affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate I may earn a small commission from qualifying purchases at no extra cost to the buyer.</em></p>
]]></description></item></channel></rss>